Inventory of the John W. Rodeffer Papers 1891-1900
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
John W. Rodeffer Papers 1891-1900
Special Collections Research Center
01/Mss. Acc. 2008.124
17.00
The John W. Rodeffer Papers are a collection of letters to John W. Rodeffer. Correspondents include family members including his mother and sister, various female friends, male friends, and others. The letters include accounts of daily life and similar information from the 1890s-1900.
Rodeffer, John W., 1864-; Rodeffer Family arrangement
Administrative Information
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open to all researchers.
Acquisition Information
The materials were acquired by Special Collections Research Center on 11/25/2008.
Biographical Note
Per 1900 census, John W. Rodeffer was born in Ohio in December, 1864. His parents were Conrad and Hannah Rodeffer. Per 1870, 1880 and 1900 census, the family lived in Rockingham, Virginia. Further information about this individual or organization may be available Special Collections Research Center Wiki
Scope and Contents
The John W. Rodeffer Papers are a collection of letters to John W. Rodeffer. Correspondents include family members including his mother and sister, various female friends, male friends, and others. The letters include accounts of daily life and similar information from the 1890s-1900.
Additional Information
Index Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Genre/Form of Material:
Correspondence
Geographic Name:
Rockingham County (Va.)--History--19th century
Topical Term:
Women--Virginia--Social life and customs
Detailed Description of the Collection
  Series 1: Family
- Family, 1894-1898
  Letters from Malinda Rodeffer (mother), Laura Rodeffer (sister), cousins and uncle.
  - Letters from Malinda Rodeffer (mother) and Laura Rodeffer (sister), 1896-1897 (1)
    Letters describing daily life while John W. Rodeffer is away at school.
  - Letters from Cousins and Uncle, 1894-1898 (2)
    Accounts of daily life; there is an embroidered ribbon with John W. Rodeffer's initials, given to him by his cousin.
  Series 2: Women
- Women, 1891-1900
  Letter from various female friends and girlfriends.
  - Stella Cline, 1891-1898 (1)
    8 letters
  - Anna, 1891-1895 (2)
    12 letters
  - L.R.S. (Laura R. Shaver), 1893-1896 (3)
    18 letters from L.R.S.
    3 letters from Lydia Weaver
  - Katie, 1895-1897 (4)
    7 letters
  - Hattie D. Long, 1892-1893 (5)
    4 letters
  - Etta Cline, 1899-1900 (6)
    3 letters
  - Various Female Friends, 1892-1897 (7)
  Series 3: Miscellaneous
- Miscellaneous
  - Letters from Male Friends, 1893-1899 (1)
    6 letters
  - Miscellaneous (2)
    19 pieces: calling cards
  - (15)